ALEXANDRA GRILLO

Manager, Risk Analytics

@ alix.clare2@gmail.com

**** 303-829-0672

501 1st St

Golden, CO

in linkedin.com/in/alixgrillo

PROFILE

Diverse and highly-motivated individual with 12 years of professional experience across several functional areas including Operations, Sales and Project Management with a strong working relationship with Information Technology, Marketing, Finance and Senior Management. Strong written and verbal communication skills with an ability to communicate on technical and strategic levels.

EXPERIENCE

Manager, Risk Analytics

Charles Schwab

🛗 Jan 2019 - Present

- Design and manage model risk management program pursuant to SR11-7, including managing regulatory examinations
- Enhance automation through systematic report building using .NET framework
- Drives process improvement by analyzing various responsibilities through developed self-assessment program

Graduate Student

University of Edinburgh

Sept 2017 - Sept 2018

- ♀ Edinburgh, Scotland, UK
- Relevant coursework includes: Machine Learning, Classification,
 Optimization, Natural Language Processing, Supply Chain, and Simulation
- Dissertation work involved optimizing team allocations in airport operations using hybrid Simulation and Heuristic Optimization techniques

Key Account Manager

Great-West Financial

m Oct 2016 - Aug 2017

- Supervised the relationship with a 20 year partner with a \$1.5 billion book of business while contributing to client retention and growing penetration within assigned partners
- Developed and maintained relationships with Retirement Income partners while responsible for implementation efforts, annual planning, issue resolution, initiative management, retention and overall account management

Project Leader

Great-West Financial

H July 2015 - Oct 2016

- ♀ Greenwood Village, CO
- Designed infrastructure for a Retirement Income Sales Concierge Desk, including internal and external training presentations, communication setup, and process documentation
- Orchestrated marketing efforts at industry conferences for product awareness in Registered Investment Advisor market - a new market opportunity

ACCOMPLISHMENTS



Competent Communicator

Active Toastmaster member including a year as Club President and launching a new club



Edinburgh Award Recipient

An award given in recognition for commitment to personal professional development



Persistence & Dedication

Shown an ability to adapt and add value to several areas of operation within Great-West Financial

LANGUAGES/SOFT SKILLS

Excel/VBA
Jira/Confluence
Tableau
C#
Github
Java
Python
R
Minitab
SOL



EDUCATION

MSc in Business Analytics

University of Edinburgh

Sept 2017 - Aug 2018

MBA in Risk Management and Insurance

University of Colorado Denver

EXPERIENCE

Assistant Manager

Great-West Financial

m July 2014 - July 2015

 Developed and managed three new functional teams inclusive of seven direct reports while assisting in management decisions and strategic planning

Business System Specialist

Great-West Financial

m Jan 2009 - July 2014

- Reconciled 10+ years of historical data on policies totaling \$6 billion while transitioning data to a new administration system
- Assisted teams with various financial reporting activities for clients with complex insurance and financial related data on a \$13 billion book of business

COLI Analyst

Great-West Financial

₩ Oct 2007 - Dec 2009

- Initiated projects to increase efficiency in periodic reporting by automating using Visual Basic
- Processed financial transactions and provided critical reporting for existing Corporate Owned Life Insurance

EDUCATION

BA in Mathematics and History

Gonzaga University

LICENSES AND DESIGNATIONS

Process Mining, Coursera

PUBLICATIONS

STTAR: A Simheuristics-Enabled Scheme for Multi-Stakeholder Coordination of Aircraft Turnaround Operations, Winter Simulation Conference 2019

STRENGTHS

Cross-Cultural Communication

Commercial Awareness

Time Management

Process Improvement

Data Analysis

Data Visualization